<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Indy Boy Mom</title>
    <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com" />
    <updated>2020-03-09T21:17:29-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Michelle K</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.indyboymom.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>&quot;We met at a men&#x27;s addiction recovery program.&quot;</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/we-met-at-a-mens-addiction-recovery-program.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/we-met-at-a-mens-addiction-recovery-program.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-07T20:35:37-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/12/Homecoming.jpg" alt="" />
                    "So, how did you two meet?" The question comes and I gulp hard, immediately the only question that comes through my mind is, how much can this person handle of "our story"? Right, well, as you can guess it wasn't a conventional way my husband,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/12/Homecoming.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>"So, how did you two meet?"  </p>
<p>The question comes and I gulp hard, immediately the only question that comes through my mind is, how much can this person handle of "our story"?  Right, well, as you can guess it wasn't a conventional way my husband, Josh and I met.  In fact, in the 9 years I have been sharing our story no one has said, "oh yea, my friends met that way too!"  Most people are surprised, possibly a little confused, but I always hope everyone walks away seeing the magnificent, gracious God my husband and I serve.</p>
<p>It was a beautiful fall day in Indiana, the kind where the leaves haven't truly begun to fall, but they are vibrant with orange, red and yellow hues of Autumn.  I was asked to help a friend take photos at an event for a local rescue mission.  It was a homecoming event, interesting thing for a rescue mission, right?  Well, this was a homecoming event for all the men who had graduated the missions men's addiction recovery program and their families. </p>
<p>It was quite a peculiar event to me.  I had been a Christian quite some time, I had known grace and I had known the Gospel, but to be honest I believed certain people would never change.  The list was small, but there was still a list and at the top of the list I was convinced alcoholics do not change.  Of course, what a small view of God that was, but it was my belief at the time.     </p>
<p>So, here I am just doing my job of taking photos of families and people enjoying the games, food and fellowship, yet in my heart I was just baffled.  There were men with their wives and children laughing together and then I would hear testimony after testimony how that man and woman were reconciled after 3 years of separation due to his drug addiction.  Testimony of that dad who had burned every single bridge so badly his son wouldn't respond to phone calls, texts, letters, nothing, so in desperation he wrote his son a letter on a $5 bill because he knew he wouldn't throw it away.  Testimony after testimony of completey broken, unreconcilable circumstances being miraculously healed, mended and stronger than ever because of Christ.  </p>
<p>Apparently as I was just doing my job and my heart was being stirred to understand what I truly know of grace and mercy there was a man in the program.  A fresh recruit, nonetheless.  I think we both still blush when he utters the words, "I saw her from afar."  Josh had entered the program just a few short months before the homecoming event, he was in the first phase of the addiction recovery program and I caught his eye that fall day.  I had no idea he existed and that day began a 2 year crush he had on me.</p>
<p>I began working for an organization that worked in Burundi, Africa so I spent the next 2 years traveling back and forth to Africa minstering to orphans and widows and accepting my calling to be a single missionary woman for life.  The camp where the homecoming event took place is a beautiful, large property in the middle of nowehere.  My friend and I would visit and I loved to go down to their church services at the camp, but most of all I enjoyed getting away from the noise of the city right before I would leave for Africa.  I also frequently served at the rescue mission serving dinner to the homeless in downtown Indy.  It was January 2011, a bitter cold night and I went to the serve dinner at the rescue mission.  I rang the door bell and a handsome young man opened the door for me with excitement and a huge smile he said, "Hi, Michelle!" I smiled and said hello as I signed in and thought, how the heck does this dude know my name?  </p>
<p>We talked as we rolled silverware and we found out we were reading the same book.  First guy I ever met who read Tozer for fun in his free time.  I told him I was off to Africa for about 2 months and he asked if I would be at the camp church service that Sunday and I said I would.  After the church service that Sunday he came up to me and walked next to me to the car, he handed me a little booklet and told me he would be praying for me during my trip.  I thanked him and that was it.  All I knew about the guy was he was 2 weeks from finishing the internship part of the program, he was pretty cute, he read Tozer and his name was Josh.  I had no idea he had a crush on me for 2 years.  </p>
<p>I remember sitting in the backseat of my friends car on the way home that day as her and another woman chatted away and I cracked open the little booklet.  My heart may have skipped a beat as I saw he had written me a note and the booklet was a devotional book.  When I got home that day I went straight to my room and cried and prayed.  Who is this guy?  I don't know this guy!  I can't have "feelings" for some dude in a flippin' addiction recovery program!!!!  But that booklet.  He wrote a note about how he would pray for me and hoped this devotional book would help give me hope and strength as I was away from my family, friends and familiar life for 2 months, that I would lean into the Lord.  He could have just given me a note.  He could have given me any book.  But he gave me a devotional with the hope that I would lean into the Lord.</p>
<p>Well, my time in Africa was incredible.  I had sent Josh a short email simply saying thank you for the booklet.  He wasn't supposed to communicate until he graduated so I did not anticipate a return e-mail, if anything.  But every single day I was in Burundi God brought Josh to my mind and I prayed for him.  The one day I did not pray for him in the morning a fellow missionary was telling a Bible story to a group and talked about Sarai and Abram going to Hebron, which was the name of the camp Josh was located.  So, I prayed for him.  He graduated from the program in February and had permission to write me back, which he promptly did the very night he graduated.  We began communicating through e-mail during my time in Burundi and the e-mails were short at first and after 2 months they were basically novels back and forth.  3 times I remember freaking out and thinking, no way, this is insane.  I cannot develop feelings for a guy who JUST graduated an addiction recovery program!!!  And 3 times I knew the Lord was reminding me of what grace I have been given and that God is always trustworthy no matter what were to happen with this guy.  </p>
<p>Well, I returned home, he asked my dad for permission to date me and 4 months later asked my parents if he could propose to me, they said yes, he proposed and I said yes!  I used to think certain people could not or maybe just would not change.  There are numerous stories of heartache and relapse and we have walked beside many friends through those difficulties.  But there is this God and He does do miracles.  He takes what once was broken and somehow He makes it whole.  He takes a heart of stone and turns it into a heart of flesh.  He takes a thief and turns him into a generous man.  He alone can take a prideful, stubborn heart and soften it more and more each day.  So, as I share this story I hope and pray the same thing I do when I answer for someone in person.  My prayer is that this magnificent God we serve would be so evident in our story that others would know Him.  "We met at a men's addiction recovery program."</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Just a Moment</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/just-a-moment.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/just-a-moment.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-07T20:35:42-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/11/tired-mom.jpg" alt="" />
                    I had one of those moments recently. You know the kind, baby is on the tabletop like a ninja eating the markers as the noodles boil over and the 5 year old was throwing a fit because he suddenly hates the noddles he loved yesterday and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/11/tired-mom.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>I had one of those moments recently.  You know the kind, baby is on the tabletop like a ninja eating the markers as the noodles boil over and the 5 year old was throwing a fit because he suddenly hates the noddles he loved yesterday and asked for 30 minutes ago, while the 6 year old gives me a complete blank stare as I give a seemingly pointless lecture for the umpteenth time about putting his markers away and away does not mean the center of the kitchen table.  I glance at the clock and see the numbers laughing at me saying you still have 2 hours until your husband is home! </p>
<p>Yep, it was one of those moments.  The kind you just want to curl up in a ball and pull your covers over your head and hope everything is in order and your children are miraculously thankful, obedient humans when you come back out.  But alas, you're a mom and that is not an option.  These humans depend on you, not to mention you cannot leave the boiling over noodles=fire hazard.  </p>
<p>In these moments, I struggle.  I am pretty sure I am going to lose my sanity every time these moments come, but so far everything seems fairly in tact.  The greatest thing about these moments in the grand scheme of motherhood is they are just moments.  They do not last.  Some may be longer than others and yes, we have had hard seasons of parenting, but again we have come through it in the end.  I hope my boys will know in the struggle and chaotic moments of life there is deep grace.  These times are no different than any other at the heart of it; we seek the Lord, we pray a lot, we lean hard into the truths of God's Word and at least I can know my boys will know what a true apology is, because most of the time I am having to apologize for poorly handling the chaotic moments. </p>
<p>I would be sorely remissed to sit there though, to stay in the struggle.  Once it is done, it is done.  Calm comes again or some simulance of it anyway.  There are moments of struggle and chaos every day it seems in motherhood, but when we lay our head on the pillow at night I hope much more often than not we are filled with memories of the moments of laughter, snuggling reading a book, those sleepy brown eyes that gave me one more glance as he says I love you, Mommy. </p>
<p>So, sweet mommas, we all have those moments.  Moments of insanity it feels like, utter chaos abounding, but lets remember they are just moments, they will pass one way or another.  Even the long seasons will eventually pass and one day when I am older and gray I hope the moments me and my boys have stored away the most are moments of great grace and joy.         </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Top 5 books for babies and toddlers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/top-5-books-for-babies-and-toddlers.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/top-5-books-for-babies-and-toddlers.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-07T20:35:47-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/10/brina-blum-d-RwmHvHPPg-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    There is nothing quite like grabbing a good book and snuggling together on the couch. I could do that for hours and thankfully so can my boys! Our youngest quickly caught on and by 1 year old he was grabbing his own book choice and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/10/brina-blum-d-RwmHvHPPg-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>There is nothing quite like grabbing a good book and snuggling together on the couch.  I could do that for hours and thankfully so can my boys!  Our youngest quickly caught on and by 1 year old he was grabbing his own book choice and bringing it to my husband or I so he could be picked up, set on our lap and read to.  Sure, there attention spans don't last long, but starting that habit and letting it be a joy for you and the baby/toddler is worth more than you know!  </p>
<p>Sarah Mackenzie in her <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0310350328/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0310350328&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=4c3c499ed4ed7878dcc2adeba2e95f26" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">book the Read Aloud Family</a> has a lot of great statistics and studies regarding the benefits of reading aloud to our kids.  It does create a love for reading, teaches and also develops relationship between the reader and the one(s) being read to.  I can attest to those results also. </p>
<p>I have heard so many times, I can't read to him, he won't sit still!  Or he doesn't seem like he is paying attention at all.  I understand.  Trust me, I have 3 boys.  I strongly believe it is not our boys not listening or paying attention (of course, there is that at times, but I am referring to the majority of the time).  Instead, I think our ideas of the ideal reading scenario must change.  Typically those of us who grew up in a school setting think if you are not still you are not learning.  There is so much research out now to prove that wrong and in fact there are those who learn BEST when moving around.  My oldest is proof.</p>
<p>When we began homeschooling he would not sit still, I thought school must be done at the table, everything quiet with no distractions and we must get through this much curriculum to be successful.  That is actually how I learn best, with it quiet and no distraction, my son however the more he moves the more engaged he is.  I do not understand it, but I do accept it because I have experienced it. </p>
<p>Kids in general and boys especially typically need to move and it is okay.  The benefits of reading out loud even if your baby or toddler is playing with their toys or chewing on a teether or eating a snack is still beneficial.  Just the sound of your voice, hearing the language, and as they age beginning to understand and follow the story line is beneficial to your sweet baby's growing mind and development.  In my opinion reading aloud to our kids even as babies is one of the most significant actions we can perform as parents for them, it is right up there with praying over them in my book.</p>
<p>So, here are 5 books I suggest because they have been fun for all 3 of my boys as babies and toddlers!</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/161067362X/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=161067362X&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=8259df52172d06c1a8fcd034df942f56" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">All Better</a>-this book is so cute!  It actually has stickers-don't be scared though (I too hate sticker books since the stickers rarely end up on the pages).  These are reuasable stickers.  They really are great, ours have lasted a year and a half and they are still sticking!  You clean the owie, kiss it, then put a bandage on it-all better!  It is an Usborne title so if you have an Usborne rep buy from them.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1523504684/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1523504684&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=e473698384e8a4569d35332f077461f4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Indestructibles</a>-these books are great for babies.  A great way to get babies used to a book and pages and of course, to read to them.  It is a step out from the normal baby board book and is a paperback of sorts, but it really is indestructible for babies.  They can chew on it/drool on it and you can clean them without ruining the pages.  They can try to tear them or throw the book (not encouraged, but hey it happens!) and they do not tear or get destroyed.  Also, they are inexpensive, usually found for under $5.  Antoher huge pro for me, a book that lasts long for multiple kids!  Every daycare should have these for sure!!</li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0746093691/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0746093691&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=c9c00eaa66eaecac6854b66923e6d838" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">That's Not My...Books</a>-Another Usborne title and there are a lot to choose from in the That's Noy My books.  This link is for That's Not My Truck, because it has been a favorite for my boys.  What we love about these books is the diffierent textures and simple wording.  It does teach them what smooth is because they are feeling the smooth trailer of the truck and at the end of the book they "find" the truck or subject of the book.  There is also a little mouse on each page, so these books are versatile in what they teach and how your child can interact.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0399226907/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0399226907&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=3da0f6a32d081696cbadc5e34ad533d1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Very Hungry Caterpillar</a>-A classic from Eric Carle, he has a lot of them but for us there was none greater than The Very Hungry Caterpillar.  I will know this book like a high school actor remembers his lines from his senior play his entire life.  Perhaps not dietarily accurate, but it does depict the process that a caterpillar goes through in one day turning into a butterfly.  My boys have always liked touching the little holes in the book that represent the caterpillar chewing through said food item.    </li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0310708257/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0310708257&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=d82a4601273df578dcad8d893394c11a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Jesus Storybook Bible</a>-I don't think kids are ever too young to hear Bible stories and engage with them.  Although this not a board book, therefore be careful with little hands tearing, it is one we would read a story from every day.  Usually at breakfast and the kids can engage in the pictures and story while the baby is safely in his high chair unable to tear, but able to engage nonetheless.  The illustrations are well done and the stories are wonderful, because Sally Lloyd-Jones truly does a great job of teaching how every story points to the Messiah, Jesus.  </li>
</ol>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Fluffy, Gluten Free Pancakes</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/fluffy-gluten-free-pancakes.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/fluffy-gluten-free-pancakes.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-07T20:35:52-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/9/kim-streicher-tKKe3aDvncE-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    Pancakes used to be my arch nemesis of food, not due to the taste but I could never cook them right. They would be burnt on the outside and mushy on the inside. Gross. So, I accepted my fate as a pancake making failure and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/9/kim-streicher-tKKe3aDvncE-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Pancakes used to be my arch nemesis of food, not due to the taste but I could never cook them right.  They would be burnt on the outside and mushy on the inside.  Gross.  So, I accepted my fate as a pancake making failure and that was that.  Until our second son had many food sensitivies and yet one of his favorite treat foods remained...the pancake. </p>
<p>I tried so many recipes.  No gluten, dairy, refined sugar, or xanthum gum. Right, how am I going to make a good tasting pancake without these ingredients?  No box mix would work, mainly because of the xanthum gum and also because I could not bring myself to pay that much for something I could surely figure out on my own.  After many and I do mean many a failed recipe we got it!  We found the successful pancake recipe with no gluten, dairy, refined sugar or xanthum gum.  And I am sharing the secret with you, they are light and fluffy and truly are delicious.  My husband actually says there will not be a better pancake and of course, my boys devour them.  Hope you too can enjoy this recipe with cleaner ingredients than most.</p>
<p><strong>Fluffy, Gluten-free Pancakes</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>2 cups flour (we use <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0047YYSSA/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B0047YYSSA&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=3acf200e8ca3f23092d766e1499d2ae1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">King Arthur's gluten free flour-no xanthum gum</a>, if there is no xanthum gum sensitivity I am sure the regular <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01JJ9H1Q8/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B01JJ9H1Q8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=ee0694182fb3665b701c67b227050122" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">King Arthur gluten free flour</a> would work.)</li>
<li>3 teaspoons baking powder</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>2 Tablespoons raw honey</li>
<li>1 1/4 cups milk (we use unsweetened vanilla almond milk, but any non dairy milk will probably do).</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>1/4 tsp vanilla extract</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine flour, baking soda and salt in a medium bowl.  In a separate bowl beat egg then add milk, vanilla, honey and stir vigorously.  Once mixed well add liquid to the medium bowl of flour and mix.  Some small clumps are okay, but there should not be a lot.  </p>
<p>Heat non stick skillet low-medium heat.  If pancake sticks use a small amount of butter-we use avocado butter or coconut oil to grease the skillet.  Pour about a 1/4 cup into skillet and wait for it to bubble then flip.  Once it is golden brown on both sides your pancake is ready.  This recipe makes about 6-8 medium pancakes.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Homemade Hot Cocoa </title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/homemade-hot-cocoa.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/homemade-hot-cocoa.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-01T16:06:10-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/8/ashkan-forouzani-lMfEoyC6K_Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    Grey clouds cover the sky, white flakes are falling and the temperature is brutal at 11° farenheit. The sting of winter is at its peak on this late January day in Indiana. We have a commin hoosier joke that says if you don't like the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/8/ashkan-forouzani-lMfEoyC6K_Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Grey clouds cover the sky, white flakes are falling and the temperature is brutal at 11° farenheit.  The sting of winter is at its peak on this late January day in Indiana.  We have a commin hoosier joke that says if you don't like the weather in Indiana wait 10 minutes.  It really was 55°F just last week.  I love Indiana and the seasons we are able to enjoy.  My boys love Indiana weather also, it's not every kid who can ride their bike on Sunday and by Tuesday afternoon be enjoying a snowball fight with the neighbors.  I</p>
<p>I love when they try to go running out of the house only to be stopped by me the winter wear police making sure they actually are sufficiently dressed to play in the snow.  I usually make myself some hot peppermint tea and sit at the kitchen table looking out as they build a snowman or throw snowballs at each other.  I always keep the window cracked so they hear me remind them no head shots, boys.  And when their little noses get so red they can no longer bear, I get up and begin the most important task.  Making the hot cocoa for them to have as soon as they unload their cold, wet clothes into the laundry basket.  </p>
<p>They come in slowly from the cold and wrap warm blankets around their little bodies and plop right down on the heat register in the kitchen to thaw out.  When everyone is in I serve them their hot cocoa and watch as they take their first sip.  They wrap their little fingers around their mug to embrace the warmth and a smile arises across each face as their tastebuds enjoy every ounce of the warm chocolate.</p>
<p>If you're used to a simple packet of hot cocoa I urge you to try this recipe.  It really is not hard at all.  The small amount of time it takes to make your hot cocoa is worth the extra MAYBE 5 minutes vs a packet of hot cocoa in every sip!  You won't regret it.  This recipe takes me maybe 10 minutes on the stove top.  </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Homemade Hot Cocoa-for 1 serving-double or triple recipe for more people</p>
<p>2 cups of milk (we use non dairy-vanilla almond milk)</p>
<p>1 Tablespoon of honey</p>
<p>1/4 teaspoon vanilla extract</p>
<p>3 tablespoons of raw cocoa powder (we buy this in bulk when it is on sale at Fresh Thyme, and stock up for the winter.  You can get it in smaller batches in the bakery aisle at your grocery store or buy it in bulk with a trusted brand <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00LNXOTDW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B00LNXOTDW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=200fd35e8ed1d8fd65b278c97fbd66e2">here</a><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00LNXOTDW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B00LNXOTDW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=200fd35e8ed1d8fd65b278c97fbd66e2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a>).</p>
<p>Heat milk on low-medium heat, add cocoa powder and honey then vanilla extract.  Stir and heat until temperature you prefer.  Enjoy!</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Fashion for all!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/fashion-for-all.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/fashion-for-all.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-09T21:17:10-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/7/stitch-fix.jpg" alt="" />
                    A mom of 3 boys writing about fashion. Here's the thing, though I do not agree with caring so much what you wear or how you look that you take away from what is truly important-your heart before God and your motives, I also think being&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/7/stitch-fix.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>A mom of 3 boys writing about fashion.  Here's the thing, though I do not agree with caring so much what you wear or how you look that you take away from what is truly important-your heart before God and your motives, I also think being a mom takes a toll in many ways on our bodies.  We as humans think of ourselves with ease, we as moms are no different, however our lives are surrounded by the needs of little ones. </p>
<p>For me thinking about what I am wearing or putting that cute piece of jewelry on that I love is definitely last on the list.  Making sure every human is clothed, went potty or has a clean diaper, everyone fed and in the car with minimal fussing and crying is success.  Making sure I get all those things done is a miracle.  So, I have found something to help me.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.stitchfix.com/invite/qkmhmxgm97?sod=w&amp;som=c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stitch Fix</a> is a great tool and I found it to actually be fun!  You pay a minimal fee ($20 or less, because they have a lot of deals!), you fill out a styling profile-pick sizes and your style AND price range preference, and a stylist picks an outfit or two for you then it ships straight to your door.  The joys of no mall traffic!  Try it all on, keep what you want and ship back (free of charge) anything you do not want.  If you don't want anything you pay nothing except the stylist charge and if you want one or a few items you pay for those and ship the rest back, if you want it all you get a larger discount and pay online.  </p>
<p>I did it for 3 months straight because I received a coupon for $20 for 3 style fixes.  Now I do it every 3 months which works great for our budget and I let my stylist know if there are any specific wants or upcoming events I'd like items for.  As a mom of 3 young ones getting out and shopping for myself will likely never make it on the priority list.  This way we budget a certain amount and I buy what I like best out of my styling fix sent straight to my door.  They have it available for Men, Women and Kids also.  I have enjoyed it and if you think you would too check it out <a href="https://www.stitchfix.com/invite/qkmhmxgm97?sod=w&amp;som=c">here</a> and you will get $25, that is your first fix covered!  What do you have to lose?  Try it for free!  <a href="https://www.stitchfix.com/invite/qkmhmxgm97?sod=w&amp;som=c">Stitch Fix</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 Books Every Mom Should Read</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/5-books-every-mom-should-read.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/5-books-every-mom-should-read.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-07T21:20:10-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/6/thought-catalog-OJZB0VUQKKc-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    We love reading! There are so many benefits to reading individually and reading to your children. My husband caught my attention before we started dating with his really cute dimple smile and also we were reading the same book. It was even a Tozer book,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/6/thought-catalog-OJZB0VUQKKc-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>We love reading!  There are so many benefits to reading individually and reading to your children.  My husband caught my attention before we started dating with his really cute dimple smile and also we were reading the same book.  It was even a Tozer book, so I knew this guy was different and his interest in deep theology attracted me to him.  If you don't like reading, audiobooks are a great option.  I always kept a book, a Bible or both in the places I would nurse the baby most often, even if I only got a few verses read or a few pages, it was something and it was helpful.  </p>
<p>So, without further ado here are 5 books I think every mom should read, in no particular order!  </p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0736976221/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0736976221&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=0658e013da59e4c14ea9fb363995bae3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Risen Motherhood</a> by Emily Jensen and Laura Wifler<br>
<ul>
<li>This book is solid in bringing the Gospel to the realities of motherhood.  No longer does Jesus seem like a distant need that all moms have, instead this book brings the depth of my desperate need for a Savior and Lord into everyday mothering.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0991277600/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0991277600&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=41f2449a927f0ce7821bfb1f785636ca" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mom Enough</a> by Rachel Jankovic, Gloria Furman, Rachel Pieh Jones, Christine Hoover, Carolyn McCulley, Trillia Newbell, Christina Fox <br>
<ul>
<li>This book is actually short articles from DesiringGod.com compiled into one book.  It is rich with truths to encourage and short enough even moms can get through the chapters and book fairly quick.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1496412664/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1496412664&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=db8c6d1fa585b14cb6d24aeb12f8057f" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Becoming Mom Strong</a> by Heidi St. John<br>
<ul>
<li>I was a heap of tears reading the Epilogue of this book, it is something I reread frequently just to gain perspective.  I respect Heidi St. John and her ministry.  She really seeks to keep the Bible at the forefront of everything she does and always seeks to encourage parents in this battle of parenthood. </li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1591280818/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1591280818&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=5c892c6d183004d80f121aaa0182887b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Loving the Little Years</a> by Rachel Jankovic<br>
<ul>
<li>This book is another short one easy enough for moms to get through actually.  Rachel does a great job in this book of helping mommas of little ones see the joys and struggles as gifts from God.  This book helps me gain perspective in these oh so tiring years with little ones.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0310350328/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0310350328&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=indyboymom-20&amp;linkId=b4aaec32b39da15e47c64c7ce77f1977" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Read-Aloud Family</a> by Sarah Mackenzie<br>
<ul>
<li>As I said we love reading as a family and this book gives great insight on research that has been done showing many ways reading aloud is beneficial for kids and families.  I think this is a great book for parents, grandparents, aunts, uncles, anyone who has a child in their life.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Happy reading, mommas, enjoy!</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dear first time mom, Part 2</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/dear-first-time-mom-part-2.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/dear-first-time-mom-part-2.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-06T20:20:30-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/5/AMJ_9376.jpg" alt="" />
                    Dear first time mom, (Letter 2) Are you feeling inadequate? Worn out? Like you can't remember when you last showered, slept or maybe you just napped in the shower? This job of motherhood is HARD. The only perfect parents are those without kids. Right? Remember&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/5/AMJ_9376.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Dear first time mom, (Letter 2)</p>
<p>Are you feeling inadequate?  Worn out?  Like you can't remember when you last showered, slept or maybe you just napped in the shower?  This job of motherhood is HARD.  The only perfect parents are those without kids.  Right?  Remember when you were single and you sat at a restaurant rolling your eyes, oh so subtly, at the screaming baby or tantrum throwing toddler in the next booth?  And those words you dared to speak, "When I have kids they definitely won't act like that."  Don't worry we were all that foolish at one point and then we had our first child.  Turns out this parenting thing is crazy hard and impossible without the grace of God.</p>
<p>Watch out for the sin trap of comparing.  Comparison will rob you of the joy of motherhood.  Don't look at every other moms posts and pictures and compare yourself and your child.  I think every time we do that and think she has it all together or I wish I had that we are saying to an almighty, all knowing, wise God, "You didn't do this right."  Or "I need something else besides what You have given me."  God gave your child to you and His ways are perfect, beyond our understanding.  He placed this child in your arms for a specific reason.  He has given you and your husband the task of raising this child in the way they should go.  Rest in Him, trust Him, follow Him and seek hard after Him.  There's nothing better you could do for your child.</p>
<p>With my first son I struggled a lot with devotions or what my time with God was to look like in that season of life.  I thought I still needed to be having half hour to an hour long time in the Word.  If I ever had a half hour sitting in that season of life I was asleep in the first 5 minutes for sure!  Your time with God will change, it is inevitable.  It is also imperitive that you still have time with God.  I personally think it looks different for each mom in each season.  God has always cared about our soul, our motives.  If we are genuinely seeking Him, wanting to know Him more and humbly desiring to obey Him I think He is honored whether we are in the Word for 10 minutes or 60 minutes.    </p>
<p>A few tips to help in the ever changing seasons of having a little one:</p>
<ul>
<li>Listen to the Bible on audio. </li>
<li>Keep a Bible next to where you nurse or often sit with the baby.</li>
<li>Listen to solid sermons or podcasts, rich in the Word and truth.  Some examples:
<ul>
<li>If your church has their sermons online relisten to the one you just heard.  Chances are you will catch something new or simply benefit from hearing it again.</li>
<li>Look at the Book from DesiringGod.com</li>
<li>John Piper sermons</li>
<li>Heidi St John podcast</li>
<li>Risen Motherhood podcast</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Every season will be different, but lean into the Lord, always seek Him and seek to know the God of the Bible more.  I think asking questions as you study God's Word is helpful even if you only ask what does this Scripture teach me about who God is?  Enjoy Him and enjoy the little blessing He gave you.  </p>
<p>For His glory alone,</p>
<p>Michelle K</p>
<p> </p>
<p>   </p>
<p>    </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Goldspoon Chili</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/award-winning-chili.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/award-winning-chili.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-01T16:36:01-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/4/calum-lewis-vA1L1jRTM70-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    Odd name for chili perhaps, but it is award winning and the award I won was in fact a gold spoon. At a friends wedding reception they had multiple people make chili and after the ceremony the bridal party took photos and guests enjoyed eating&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/4/calum-lewis-vA1L1jRTM70-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Odd name for chili perhaps, but it is award winning and the award I won was in fact a gold spoon.  At a friends wedding reception they had multiple people make chili and after the ceremony the bridal party took photos and guests enjoyed eating then voting on their favorite chili.  I won a gift card and a gold glitter sprayed spoon trophy, we had a blast!  Without further ado here is the winning chili recipe!  </p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ingredients</strong></li>
<li>2 pounds ground beef chuck</li>
<li>1 pound Italian sausage</li>
<li>½ pound bacon (okay, we usually do 1 pound of bacon and 1/2 pound of sausage!)</li>
<li>3 cans (15 oz) chili beans drained</li>
<li>1 can (15 oz) chili beans in spicy sauce</li>
<li>2 (28 oz) cans diced roasted tomatoes with juice</li>
<li>1 (6 oz) can tomato paste</li>
<li>1 large onion</li>
<li>3 stalks celery</li>
<li>1 green bell pepper</li>
<li>1 red bell pepper</li>
<li>4 cubes beef boullion or we use 2 tablespoons liquid aminos</li>
<li>¼-1/2 cup water</li>
<li>¼ cup chili powder</li>
<li>1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce</li>
<li>2 garlic cloves pressed</li>
<li>1 tablespoon oregano leaves</li>
<li>2 teaspoons ground cumin</li>
<li>2 teaspoons siracha chili sauce (1 tsp for less spice)</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dried basil</li>
<li>1 1/2 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>1 teaspoon black pepper</li>
<li>1 teaspoon cayenne pepper (1/2 tsp for less spice or 1 1/2 for more if you're braver than I)</li>
<li>1 teaspoon paprika</li>
<li>½ tablespoon sugar (we use honey or maple syrup)</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Directions</strong></p>
Brown beef and sausage in large skillet over medium heat. Drain.<br>Cook bacon in skillet over medium heat.<br>Combine meats.<br>Chop peppers, onion and celery then heat over medium-high heat until slightly brown.<br>Add all ingredients to crock pot and cook on low 4-5 hours.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dear First Time Mom Part 1</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/dear-first-time-mom-part-1.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/dear-first-time-mom-part-1.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-07T20:36:04-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/3/AMJ_9340.jpg" alt="" />
                    Dear first time mom, I reached out to a few friends and have compiled some advice and encouragement for you as you begin your new journey of motherhood. Maybe you can feel that little bundle swirling around inside you as you read this or maybe&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/3/AMJ_9340.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Dear first time mom,</p>
<p>I reached out to a few friends and have compiled some advice and encouragement for you as you begin your new journey of motherhood. Maybe you can feel that little bundle swirling around inside you as you read this or maybe you’re up at midnight with pregnancy heartburn.  Whatever your scenario is right now, the most important thing to know is, this baby is a gift from God.  Psalm 127:3 says, “Children are a blessing, a gift from the Lord.”  There is no plainer way to say it, and I find it interesting and profound that God did not put stipulations on when a child is a blessing.  For example, He did not say children are a blessing if they're born in wedlock, when you’re expecting him/her.  Or to those who have enough money saved up to pay for everything the baby needs in the first year of life, He doesn’t even put the stipulation that the child must come from your womb to be a blessing and a gift.  He simply says, “Children are a blessing, a gift from the Lord.”  So, sweet momma who is tired already, remember this child is a blessing and a gift from God Himself so be thankful for the gift.</p>
<p>Advice you have probably already received is to rest when your baby rests. There is a reason you have already received this advice, because it is true and you should do it. More than that you should not feel guilty about the dishes, laundry or mess in the living room you should just REST.  Raising, training and healing are hard work.  Also, even when the baby is awake take time to just enjoy the gift of this life. The laundry, dishes and dust will always be there, but these precious moments to watch your child grow and learn will fly by.  Try to relish them before they’re gone.</p>
<p>Be gracious. You and your husband are new to this parenting thing, and the truth is it doesn’t matter if you have 1 or 10 kids we are all fully reliant on the grace of God every day in life and parenting.  Take time AWAY from the baby even if it is just an hour to talk to your husband, be with him, ask him about his work, remember he was the one you fell in love with first and he will be the one holding your hand when you’re wrinkly and gray-haired.  Nurture your relationship with your husband.  Accept help offered by friends to babysit or bring a meal or hold the baby.  All of these things are taking something off your plate and you will be a better woman for it.  Be gracious with your husband as he learns you in the role of motherhood, it won’t come overnight to either of you but stick together, remember you’re on the same team and God has given you a great task TOGETHER to nurture and raise a child in the way they should go.</p>
<p>Now pray over that sweet baby and get some rest, sweet momma.</p>
<p>I’ll write more later, sincerely,</p>
<p>         Michelle K</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
