<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Indy Boy Mom</title>
    <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com" />
    <updated>2020-12-06T14:28:13-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Michelle K</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.indyboymom.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Surviving and Thriving: Discouragement in Motherhood</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/surviving-and-thriving-discouragement-in-motherhood.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/surviving-and-thriving-discouragement-in-motherhood.html</id>

        <updated>2020-12-06T14:28:06-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/30/thought-catalog-TAzjNSkLvlA-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    Recently I was talking with a friend who is in the thick of mothering little ones. For me when we had 2 under 2 and 3 years old it was hard. Very hard for me. In fact, I am not joking that I was convinced&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/30/thought-catalog-TAzjNSkLvlA-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Recently I was talking with a friend who is in the thick of mothering little ones.  For me when we had 2 under 2 and 3 years old it was hard.  Very hard for me.  In fact, I am not joking that I was convinced someone would not survive and the most likely victim would be me.  I wish I had great encouraging advice that made my friends circumstances and the hardness of parenting the little years a bit lighter for her, but honestly, I had nothing to offer her.  </p>
<p>I remember at that same season of life hearing a speaker at a moms group and the topic was not just surviving but thriving in motherhood.  At the end of it I felt inspirired, but I would say the inspiration quickly wore off as soon as I went to pick up my son from the nursery and tried to buckle his defiant self into the carseat.  As I look back on motherhood thus far there are few times I would say there is a lot of thriving going on.  I think we are so prone to discouragement when we don't feel like we're thriving as moms.</p>
<p>As moms we feel like we are living in the movie Groundhog Day...forever.  Somehow the seasons change, but my boys are still doing the exact thing I could have sworn I disciplined them for yesterday, and the day before that and before that.  </p>
<p>Perhaps you're in that boat.  Maybe it isn't the exact same circumstances, but maybe you can relate a little or a lot.  Maybe you're the mom holding a newborn and feeling the exhaustion of constant feedings and diaper changes and wardrobe changes because of the spit up or diaper malfunction.  Perhaps you're the mom with the toddler who has found he can now speak your language and enjoys yelling, "no, mommy!".  Or perhaps you're the mom of the teenager who is struggling at school and your own heart is breaking as you watch your child struggle in battle.  Whatever your season, whatever your circumstancial struggle is, we have all been there: discouragement.  </p>
<p>We've lost sight in the valley of discouragement of the final destination-the mountain top, and that is okay.  I don't believe discouragement is a sin.  Perhaps when we are discouraged we are more apt to sin in various ways (gluttony, laziness, anger, or a myriad of selfishness), but to be discouraged is not a sin.  In our times of discouragement it is an opportunity.  An opportunity for faithfulness.  Faithful obedience to the next thing.  The next thing may not be glamorous, the next thing may not and probably will not provide relief.  But if we are faithful by His grace to obey Him and to do the next thing He has called us to do: get up and feed the baby, discipline the toddler in love again, ask for forgiveness again, pray over your child again; well, this is how we walk out of discouragement.  Not over night usually, but step by step.  I hope I can look back at the times of discouragment in motherhood and say by God's grace we didn't JUST survive it, and I highly doubt there will be many times I feel like I thrived in it, but I hope to be faithful through it.     </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Gluten Free, Dairy Free Chocolate Chip Muffins</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/gluten-free-dairy-free-chocolate-chip-muffins.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/gluten-free-dairy-free-chocolate-chip-muffins.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-29T21:13:46-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/29/IMG_9204.jpg" alt="" />
                    It is hard to find a good muffin that is gluten free that isn't overpowered by coconut or almond flour, in my opinion. We have found a gluten free flour that works well as a substitute for recipes that call for flour and we always&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/29/IMG_9204.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>It is hard to find a good muffin that is gluten free that isn't overpowered by coconut or almond flour, in my opinion.  We have found a gluten free flour that works well as a substitute for recipes that call for flour and we always substitute honey for the sugar.  So, with some tweaking I finally found a good consistency in these chocolate chip muffins that the boys love.</p>
<p>We also like these because they only make about 10 muffins for us which between 5 of us is reasonable and doesn't leave any leftovers for us to overeat on.  These can be kept in a tupperware or ziploc bag for a few days or can be frozen also.  Hope you enjoy!</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Chocolate Chip Muffins </p>
<p>Ingredients</p>
<p>1 1/2 cups gluten free all purpose flour-we use a brand at our local grocery called King Arthur, but as long as it is gluten free and all purpose, it should work fine.</p>
<p>1/4 cup or less honey</p>
<p>2 teaspoons baking powder</p>
<p>1/4 teaspoon salt</p>
<p>1 egg</p>
<p>1 1/4 cup milk-we use rice milk, but any non dairy milk should work.</p>
<p>1/4 cup oil</p>
<p>1 teaspoon vanilla</p>
<p>1 cup chocolate chips-we use the brand Enjoy Life</p>
<p>Directions:</p>
<p>In a medium mixing bowl beat the egg.  Add the milk, oil, vanilla and honey and mix well.  In a larger bowl add flour, baking powder and salt and wisk together.  Add the wet ingredients from the medium bowl to the larger bowl and wisk well until smooth with few or no lumps.  Fold in chocolate chips.  Pour into a muffin tin and bake at 350 for 10-12 minutes or until center is not gooey.  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Always a Time of Thanks</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/always-a-time-of-thanks.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/always-a-time-of-thanks.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-20T06:58:48-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/28/patrick-fore-b_SHPU5M3nk-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    I was reading a book (Thanksgiving on Plymouth Plantation by Diane Stanley) with my kids recently and learned that it was Abraham Lincoln who made the last Thursday in November the official Thanksgiving holiday. It was also not set as a time to remember the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/28/patrick-fore-b_SHPU5M3nk-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>I was reading a book (<em>Thanksgiving on Plymouth Plantation by Diane Stanley</em>) with my kids recently and learned that it was Abraham Lincoln who made the last Thursday in November the official Thanksgiving holiday.  It was also not set as a time to remember the pilgrims and indians having a time of thanks together; that is called a fall festival which began hundreds of years prior to Thanksgiving Day and was an annual celebration feast after the harvest between the pilgrims and indians.  </p>
<p>So, the actual Thanksgiving Day.  A day established in America during the middle of the Civil War.  A time to set aside in the midst of a war torn, divided country to give thanks to God for His faithfulness and blessings.  Seems ironic, huh?  To give thanks and think on blessings when not much is "going right".  Perhaps we should do the same though.  2020 has been a difficult year for most.  But if we take time out to remember all the good things that happened, the laughter even if it was over Zoom or Facetime and the blessings even of technology perhaps we can begin to agree with Abraham Lincoln, in a time of tumult there really is still a lot to be grateful for.  </p>
<p>Ideas to spur on thankfulness with your family:</p>
<ul>
<li>A thankfulness tree:  Grab a branch from the backyard and put it in a cup with rocks or something heavy to keep it in.  Then take scrap pieces of paper (if you're crafty cut them into leaves) and each day have each person write down what they are thankful for.</li>
<li>A time of thanks, each night at dinner go around the table and ask each person what they are thankful for that day.</li>
<li>Keep a thankfulness journal personally or as a family or better yet, both!  Write down what you're thankful for each day and be sure to look back at how faithful God has been and how many things we can give thanks for in all times.  </li>
<li>Go on a prayer of thanks walk, thank God for different things your entire walk.</li>
<li>Look up scripture references that include thanks and read them as a family.</li>
</ul>
<p>Cultivating a heart of gratitude is important in our lives and important to help guide our children toward also.  Have you ever spent time with someone who has "the whole world against them" at all times?  It doesn't matter what is going on in their lives, words of thanks are rarely uttered.  On the contrary I am not saying pretend everything is okay when it is a difficult season, however, I fully agree with President Lincoln that it is always a time of thanks.  There are always things to be grateful for, we just need to train our eyes and hearts to see them more often.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Montana and Road Trippin&#x27; With Kids</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/montana-and-road-trippin-with-kids.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/montana-and-road-trippin-with-kids.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-13T13:35:44-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/27/IMG_0005.JPG" alt="" />
                    Okay, first thing is first, if you have not traveled to Montana, GO. You must go. I have now traveled to 47 states, missing only Idaho, Hawaii and Alaska, in my opinion Montana is the most underated state. Why go? It is beautiful, it has&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/27/IMG_0005.JPG" alt="" />
                <p>Okay, first thing is first, if you have not traveled to Montana, GO.  You must go.  I have now traveled to 47 states, missing only Idaho, Hawaii and Alaska, in my opinion Montana is the most underated state.  Why go?  It is beautiful, it has rolling hills, flat fields, mountains and wildlife galore.  The people.  Oh the people we met were the real deal.  Genuine and wonderful.  It is far away, because basically even if you live in a neighboring state you're going to be driving quite a while to get to a city or a village in Montana, but it will be worth the drive.  Not sure about driving?  Let me tell you how we not only survived but thrived and had a blast as a family driving 47 hours total from Indy to Glasgow, Montana. </p>
<p>First, audio dramas.  Different and better than audiobooks which have one narrator usually and my boys do not like the way the narrator uses "different" voices for different characters and I must agree, it can be annoying.  We have 3 favorite audio dramas.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="adventuresinodyssey.com" title="Adventures in Odyssey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Adventures in Odyssey</a>- I think most people in the Christian community are familiar with Focus on the Family and a lot are already familiar with Adventures in Odyssey.  I remember listening to AIO when I was a kid so a few years ago when our older boys were just 5 and 3 I checked an AIO CD out from our church library.  That was it.  The entire family was hooked.  We are still old school and buy CD's for our older vehicles but there are MP3 options and download options available too.  Wholesome, family oriented, real life and fun entertainment for the entire family.  </li>
<li><a href="jonathanpark.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Jonathan Park">Jonathan Park</a>- This one is more rare, but another favorite adventure series for the family.  We have listened to Jonathan grow up and heard his family seek the Lord and make prayer and the validity and inerrancy of Scripture of utmost importance.  Jonathan Park series focuses on creation science and refutes evolution in an exciting, informative and engaging way even for younger kids.</li>
<li><a href="lamplighter.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Lamplighter">Lamplighter</a>- Our first Lamplighter introduction was at a homeschool convention and we asked the employee what she would suggest for a new to Lamplighter family with young boys.  She suggested Teddy's Button and it is to this day the boys favorite.  Lamplighter audio dramas are intense, captivating and chok-full of excitement.  They have age recommendations that I would stick with especially for the more sensitive younger ones.  Lamplighter books are also great and we passed many a mile marker reading or listening to Lamplighter.</li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<p>A few other ways we passed the time on our long drive was tackle box snacks.  Every morning before we hit the road I filled up each boys tackle box with snacks.  The rules were, these are your snacks for the trip today, period.  Eat them too quickly?  O'well that is what you get.  Drop them on the floor or in your carseat?  O'well that is what you get (and you will be helping clean out the car at our destination).  We got these the night before departure at Walmart for a few bucks each.  </p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/27/IMG_9339.JPG" alt="" width="4032" height="3024"></p>
<p>There are a lot of printable game ideas too, my all time favorite is the license plate game.  You don't have to have a printable just write down every different state license plate you see and see if you can get all 50.  The alphabet game is another fun one, see who can get through the alphabet by seeing letters on signs or other vehicles.  X is always hard and a fun one to be stuck at for a while!</p>
<p>Lastly, all props to <a href="thedatingdivas.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="The Dating Divas">The Dating Divas </a>for this idea, but I made a banner with 12 Do Not Open Until signs.  At each location listed they were given a small bag or small present to open.  Each one contained either a book, an activity book, a game, or they're favorite: candy.  It was something they looked forward too and also a win for us that it kept us from hearing, "I'm bored" or "are we there yet?" a million times.</p>
<p>So, now that you have some ideas, go have an adventure with your family!  Do not be afraid to roadtrip together.  Even if it is just an hour or two away, go!  Enjoy your kids, don't turn a screen on and ask them questions, play a game together, enjoy an audio drama that you are so glued to that they ask you to keep listening even when you arrive!  Many people said we were crazy for taking 3 boys in a car for 47 hours, but let me tell you, my husband and I do not regret it and I am positive we never will.  Our kids have memories they will keep forever and we certainly do too.  There are always difficult times (like saying stop running in the hotel room a hundred times an hour), but the good far out weighs the bad when you're engaged and focused on your family.  And may I suggest Big Sky Country, Montana is a great place to start! </p>
<p>  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Adventure Points</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/adventure-points.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/adventure-points.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-13T13:42:45-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/26/aaker-RYjRmOQtlUA-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    Are you tired of your kids saying they're bored? Do you struggle with having too much screen time at your house? Do you wish your kids were more active, especially during summer break? I felt the same way. When we aren't in the normal school&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/26/aaker-RYjRmOQtlUA-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Are you tired of your kids saying they're bored?  Do you struggle with having too much screen time at your house?  Do you wish your kids were more active, especially during summer break?  I felt the same way.  When we aren't in the normal school routine I get lazy just as fast as they do it seems!  So, I had an idea and created something I called our Summer Adventure Points.  </p>
<p>The kids had to complete so many tasks worth so many points before they could have screen time.  It also helped encourage siblings to actually get along, play together and DO something not just sit in front of a screen or tell me they're bored or stand in front of the fridge saying, "I'm hungry, can we eat lunch now?" At 8am exactly 10 minutes after they ate breakfast.  If they came to me with a request to watch something or play on the Ipad or if they dared to complain about being bored I simply sent them to the Summer Adventure board and told them to pick something and do it.  It ended up being a fun way to spend time together even on the dreaded rainy days.  </p>
<p>Here is a free Adventure Point Sheet you can print out for your family.  If you want to tweak it to suite your family more I actually wrote ours out on a poster board and hung it up in the entryway.  We kept track daily on our calendar and then weekly there is a section to write in your total weekly points.  We did ours for 3 months so 500 points was a  challenge to some, but definitely attainable!  </p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/26/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-1.41.24-PM.png" alt="" width="1152" height="812"> <img class="post__image" src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/26/~dollarAdventure-points.xlsx" alt=""></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Great books for kids about animals</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/great-books-for-kids-about-animals.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/great-books-for-kids-about-animals.html</id>

        <updated>2020-04-10T15:02:31-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/25/aaron-burden-6jYoil2GhVk-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    I don't know if I have met a kid who does not like animals. Perhaps some animals, like a snake or spiders, but overall most kids love most animals. If your child is struggling to be engaged in reading a great way to combat that&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/25/aaron-burden-6jYoil2GhVk-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>I don't know if I have met a kid who does not like animals.  Perhaps some animals, like a snake or spiders, but overall most kids love most animals.  If your child is struggling to be engaged in reading a great way to combat that is finding books they would be engaged in, like books about animals.  This is a list of books or book series that we have thoroughly enjoyed.  Some are funny, some are serious, but every single one has captivated my boys.  Most of them I read to them, so whether you are reading to your kids or they are old enough to read them, these main character animal books are sure to engage your child!</p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062312189/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0062312189&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;linkId=8ff1c67399869367da4213818594c2d1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Paddington by Michael Bond</a>- Chances are you have already heard of Paddington, it is a classic.  This bear is so loveable and his inadvertent mischeif will keep your whole family smiling and laughing the entire book.  My oldest son loved Paddington so much for a few weeks he was found wearing a blue coat and begging to put a marmalade sandwich in his red hat in case of an emergency.  The first movie is quite cute also and fun to watch after reading the book.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/168263163X/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=168263163X&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;linkId=c27c5ef241ad2eb4270dafb7235cf6ef" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dog Chronicles by Alison Hart</a>-My oldest came upon these books at the library and we have fallen in love with them!  If you want to engage your kids in history while following the heroism of a dog they will fall in love with, these are the books for you.  We were all glued to every page.  If your kids are 6 and under it may be harder to hold their attention as there are not many pictures, but even my 5 year old boy loved these books.  They follow a specific dog into an action packed story that will have you and your kids unable to put the book down.  There are 4 different titles we have found:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/168263163X/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=168263163X&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;linkId=dc027ccefbf6eafa3c93bf172c9111ea" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Finder: Coal Mine Dog</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1682630897/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1682630897&amp;linkId=a7d7fbad4f4cd85237321afd70dc0ffd" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Leo: Dog of the Sea</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B078BCRDXC/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B078BCRDXC&amp;linkId=9f8ce26d80daa67d98181060551e7af2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Darling: Mercy Dog of World War I</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0789TRDS3/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B0789TRDS3&amp;linkId=a089524b4adcf8673216a2585be02170" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Murphy: Gold Rush Dog</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0763657093/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0763657093&amp;linkId=fa456a834137f1290ecb1a7ba2fc3d24" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mercy Watson by Kate DiCamillo</a>: You may or may not be familiar with Mercy Watson a pet pig who loves toast with a great deal of butter on it, but you are probably familiar with this wonderful, engaging author: Kate DiCamillo.  She is probably most famous for <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0763680869/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0763680869&amp;linkId=ef543aae16b391102ec266ca89224d07" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Because of Winn Dixie</a> or <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0763680893/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0763680893&amp;linkId=245fbf4072a53899254961962b815aaa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Tale of Despereaux</a> both later made into great movies.  Mercy Watson books are illustrated by <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1536208647/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1536208647&amp;linkId=3d744481504a830833aef0d685817d6a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chris Van Dusen</a> an excellent illustrator with pictures that keep kids of all ages engaged and intrigued in the story.  </p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062360639/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0062360639&amp;linkId=2d89bd71c73e263813479686f3b5e5f2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Henry Huggins by Beverly Cleary</a>-A Newberry Medal Award winning author writes these hilarous books about a boy and his new dog Ribsy.  You and your kids will love these fun tales with Henry and Ribsy and the mischief they find in their daily adventures as best friends.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0890514569/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0890514569&amp;linkId=23ba0a7938d1dcab56eadb8e058bae33" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Marvels of Creation by Buddy Davis</a>-If it's fiction your kids are more interested in these books will hit the spot.  The photos are gorgeous and there is a page dedicated to each animal so the information load is perfect for a younger or older reader. There are 3 books in this series featuring animals from different areas.  These are also from a Biblical worldview and creationist view which is a breath of fresh air for us!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0890514585/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0890514585&amp;linkId=0ec9e7a881f3cc6a0b985141ff9d5a5e" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sensational Sea Creatures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0890514569/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0890514569&amp;linkId=23ba0a7938d1dcab56eadb8e058bae33" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Magnificent Mammals</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0890514577/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=308be-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0890514577&amp;linkId=42f1b7b4add3f839e1bfcccf8a9f30c6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Breathtaking Birds</a></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Disclosure: Bear in mind that some of the links in this post are affiliate links and if you go through them to make a purchase I will earn a commission. Keep in mind that I link these companies and their products because of their quality and not because of the commission I receive from your purchases. The decision is yours, and whether or not you decide to buy something is completely up to you. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Quarantine Care Packages</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/quarantine-care-packages.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/quarantine-care-packages.html</id>

        <updated>2020-04-05T18:09:50-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/24/Screen-Shot-2020-04-05-at-6.02.25-PM.png" alt="" />
                    Most of us are stuck at home and some people are going crazy! It is a tough transition for a lot of people and I can't imagine having a work from home job and having younger elementary kids you're trying to help with this e-learning.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/24/Screen-Shot-2020-04-05-at-6.02.25-PM.png" alt="" />
                <p>Most of us are stuck at home and some people are going crazy!  It is a tough transition for a lot of people and I can't imagine having a work from home job and having younger elementary kids you're trying to help with this e-learning.  It is difficult and it is a great time for us as Christians to show love to our neighbors even if we can't be closer than 6 feet away.  </p>
<p>Here is an idea of what we did!  The options are limitless I am sure, so be creative in your own way and bless your neighbors!  We did a movie night quarantine care package!  You can go to <a href="https://premium.vcdelivery.com/redbox/?cid=lp:link:gifts:8:15:2018" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redbox.com</a> and get a promo code gift card.  It may seem confusing, but I purchased the 5 promos gift card and had it sent to my own e-mail.  Then once it came to my e-mail I wrote the promo codes on the print outs to hand out to each neighboy.</p>
<p>Once you get the promo codes I printed the <a href="http://www.acupfullofsass.com/teacherappreciationgift/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redbox move night printable from here</a>.  I liked these because a lot of them were teacher specific ones, but these were more generic so I could use them for neighbors.  We got .50 gift bags, gave them a few hundred grand (the candy bar) for hard times, microwave popcorn and wrote a note of encouragement.  Normally we would do this anonymously but this time we wanted to put our names and phone numbers if our neighbors needed anything to let us know.  We delivered them to neighbors by placing them, oh so stealthily on their front porch.  Great way for kids to serve!  This is the time for the church to rise up, to serve, to love others and to be the hands and feet of Christ even if we can't do that face to face.  I hope this inspires you to serve your neighbors, unebelievers or friends and family in some way during this time also!</p>
<div class="gallery"   >
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/24/gallery/Screen-Shot-2020-04-05-at-6.02.25-PM.png" ><img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/24/gallery/Screen-Shot-2020-04-05-at-6.02.25-PM-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="646" height="865"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">Package contents</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/24/gallery/Screen-Shot-2020-04-05-at-6.08.00-PM.png" ><img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/24/gallery/Screen-Shot-2020-04-05-at-6.08.00-PM-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="645" height="862"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">Delivery method</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/24/gallery/F95D7802-8926-40BE-A61B-8A3EBD6396E3.jpeg" ><img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/24/gallery/F95D7802-8926-40BE-A61B-8A3EBD6396E3-thumbnail.jpeg" alt="" width="720" height="782"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">Stealth mode delivery</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>At home activities with kids (no screens)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/at-home-activities-with-kids-no-screens.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/at-home-activities-with-kids-no-screens.html</id>

        <updated>2020-04-02T20:39:29-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/23/ryan-wallace-azA1hLbjBBo-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    There are so many amazing resources being offered during these tough times for free or great deals. I know how tempting it is to just turn the screen on for them, but here are some neat alternatives to screen time! Adventures in Odyssey-we LOVE Adventures&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/23/ryan-wallace-azA1hLbjBBo-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>There are so many amazing resources being offered during these tough times for free or great deals.  I know how tempting it is to just turn the screen on for them, but here are some neat alternatives to screen time!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.whitsend.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Adventures in Odyssey</a>-we LOVE Adventures in Odyssey.  We have a lot of the CD's and as soon as we get in the car the boys ask, "May we listen to Odyssey?"  even when we pull in the garage they ask, "May we keep listening to Odyssey?".  It is a favorite for the whole family.  Right now they have a 4 week free trial for their Kids Club.  My favorites are the episodes that are from historical time periods, like the recent Titanic episodes.  Some you may want to listen with your kids (especially to explain to a more sensitive child) but overall we have listened from about 4 years old up.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.educationalinsights.com/at-home-activities-for-kids" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Educational Insights</a>-this site is full of ideas!  Craft ideas, game ideas, even schedule ideas by age.  It is a great resource for ages 1-8 years old.  They even have videos, which I always find helpful for the crafts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.learningresources.com/free-at-home-learning-essentials" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learning Resources</a>-this site has free printables, coloring pages and learning tips by subject or grade Preschool-5th. A lot of their workbooks are free and able to be printed.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hand2mindathome.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">hand2mind</a>-this is a great resource for Spanish speakers, as they have their conent in Spanish and English.  There are daily schedules, activities by grade (K-5), and printable manipulatives even.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cooking with kids</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/cooking-with-kids.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/cooking-with-kids.html</id>

        <updated>2020-04-02T14:55:08-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/22/johnny-mcclung-0aC-3Gt7jF4-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    During this time being home more often than usual I have been enjoying each night a different boy cooking by my side. It's been a lot of fun and a great bonding time together. I stumbled upon this website kidscookrealfood.com and I absolutely love her&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/22/johnny-mcclung-0aC-3Gt7jF4-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>During this time being home more often than usual I have been enjoying each night a different boy cooking by my side.  It's been a lot of fun and a great bonding time together.  I stumbled upon this website <a href="https://sl290.isrefer.com/go/kcrf/Indyboymom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">kidscookrealfood.com</a> and I absolutely love her process!  She does a great job of meeting a child where they're at and helping teach the parents/guardians how to let the child help in the kitchen.  I wanted to highlight this because right now she is offering a <a href="https://sl290.isrefer.com/go/kcrf/Indyboymom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2 week free trial</a> and after that for a limited time you can get a 2 month membership for just $19.  This is a great deal, and you don't have to decide until your two week free trial is up anyway.  </p>
<p>So, enjoy the time with your kids!  Bake and cook in the kitchen together.  Teach them skills (or maybe learn them yourself) that you normally wouldn't take the time to learn together.  Now is your chance and I highly recommend <a href="https://sl290.isrefer.com/go/kcrf/Indyboymom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this course</a> to help you!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Free/inexpensive educational resources</title>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle K</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.indyboymom.com/freeinexpensive-educational-resources.html"/>
        <id>https://www.indyboymom.com/freeinexpensive-educational-resources.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-27T19:15:09-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/21/plush-design-studio-q10VITrVYUM-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    With all that is going on there are some amazing free trials and free subscriptions going on too! Business are getting creative and also just wanting to meet a great need that is out there currently. Here is a list of 4 education resources that&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.indyboymom.com/media/posts/21/plush-design-studio-q10VITrVYUM-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>With all that is going on there are some amazing free trials and free subscriptions going on too!  Business are getting creative and also just wanting to meet a great need that is out there currently.  Here is a list of 4 education resources that I highly recommend!  Some of them are free for a limited time only.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://iahe.net/keep-calm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IAHE.net</a>
<ul>
<li>Indiana Homeschool Convention is online for free until April 10th.  After April 10th I believe there will be a small fee, but this is an amazing resource.  Not only are there solid teachings and workshops to equip and encourage home education there is also an online exhibit hall to check out curriculum, books, educational games and the list goes on!  I attend the Indiana Homeschool Convention each year and have never been disappointed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://teach-them-diligently-at-home.heysummit.com/?utm_source=ActiveCampaign&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=Teach+Them+Diligently+AT+HOME+Is+Coming+Soon%21&amp;utm_campaign=TTDatHome+is+OPEN%21%21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Teach Them Diligently</a>
<ul>
<li>I have not been to a Teach Them Diligently conference yet, but I am extremely excited that they are offering so much of their conference online right now.  It is $20 (super cheap for so much GREAT info) or $60 which includes a membership (membership is normally $99, so another great deal).  I really respect the leadership at Teach Them Diligently and this is another great resource for looking into homeschooling or for veteran homeschoolers.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://homeschoolsummits.com/parenting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Parent Summit</a>
<ul>
<li>This is a parent summit, lot's of solid speakers encouraging parents.  We have attended their online homeschool summits before and enjoyed the Biblical teaching we received so I am sure this new parenting summit will be uplifting and Biblical also.  It is free.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="www.daveramsey.com/hope" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Financial Peace University</a>
<ul>
<li>We love Dave Ramsey and I respect that during this difficult time financially for so many people Ramsey Solutions is offering the Financial Peace University class absolutely free for 2 weeks.  You can totally binge watch it.  Even if you have already seen it, chances are it could be an older version you saw and you will learn something new or hear something afresh in it.  This is a GREAT tool to pass on to friends or family as we all know people drastically impacted financially through these recent times.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
